<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The famous and virtuous necklaces; one of them being of no greater weight than a small nutmeg, absolutely easing children in breeding teeth without pain; thereby preventing feavers, ruptures, convulsions, rickets, and such attendant distempers ...</title>
            <author>Choke, John.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B20208</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888730</idno>
  <idno type="VID">195937</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2264183389</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C3920B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.112.f.9[132]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[194]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231733</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888730</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888730e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B20208)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 195937)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:1[133], E8:2[193])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The famous and virtuous necklaces; one of them being of no greater weight than a small nutmeg, absolutely easing children in breeding teeth without pain; thereby preventing feavers, ruptures, convulsions, rickets, and such attendant distempers ...</title>
                  <author>Choke, John.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption and first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Imprint and author from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Advertising --  Drugs --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Physicians --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Teeth --  Care and Hygiene --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:195937:1"/>
            <head>The Famous and Virtuous <hi>Necklaces;</hi>
            </head>
            <p>One of Them<lb/> BEing of no greater weight than a small <hi>Nutmeg,</hi> absolutely easing Children in Breeding <hi>Teeth</hi> without <hi>Pain;</hi> thereby preventing <hi>Feavers, Ruptures, Convulsions, Rickets,</hi> and such attendant Distempers, to the Admiration of thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sands in the City of <hi>London,</hi> and Counties adjacent, who have ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perienced the same, to their great comfort, and satisfaction of the Parents, of the Children, that have used them: Besides the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crease in the <hi>Bills of Mortality</hi> apparent (within this Year and half) of above one half of what formerly Dyed; and are now Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed to Sale at <hi>Five Shillings</hi> each <hi>Necklace,</hi> viz.</p>
            <list>
               <item>At Major <hi>Chokes,</hi> at the <hi>Kings-Head,</hi> nigh St. <hi>Clements</hi> Church.</item>
               <item>At Mr. <hi>Whiteheads</hi> at the <hi>Black-Boy</hi> in <hi>Canon-street,</hi> against <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don-Stone.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>White</hi> Grocer in the <hi>Old-Baily.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>
                  <hi>Mr. Barnes</hi> Coat-seller, at the <hi>Cherry-Tree,</hi> by <hi>Strand-Bridge.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Green</hi> Iron-monger over against St. <hi>Dunstons</hi>-Church in <hi>Fleet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>street,</hi> where the said Major doth most reside.</item>
               <item>Mrs. <hi>Mullineux</hi> Sempstresse, at the <hi>Sun</hi> and <hi>Star</hi> in St. <hi>James</hi>'s-<hi>Fields,</hi> near St. <hi>James</hi>'s-<hi>street.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Jarvis,</hi> at the <hi>George</hi> in <hi>Milk-street.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>West</hi> Hosier, in <hi>Russel-street,</hi> near <hi>Drury-lane.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Whiskers</hi> Upholsterer, in <hi>King-street Westminster,</hi> near the <hi>Abbey.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mrs. <hi>Suttons</hi> a sempstress, next the <hi>Rose-Tavern</hi> without <hi>Temple-Bar.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Sclater</hi> at the <hi>Red-Cross</hi> in <hi>Newgate-street.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Tho. Barns</hi> Coat-seller at the <hi>Black-Boy</hi> in <hi>Cheap-side,</hi> near St. <hi>Pauls.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Flower,</hi> Clark of St. <hi>Katherine-Coleman</hi> in <hi>Pye-Alley,</hi> in <hi>Fan-Church-street.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Turner</hi> Book-seller in <hi>Holbourn,</hi> near <hi>Turn-stile.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Woolger</hi> Millenar, at the <hi>Turk</hi> and <hi>Slave</hi> in <hi>Jewen-street.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Wyat,</hi> against the <hi>Fleet-Prison,</hi> Upholsterer.</item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Bridges</hi> Coate-seller at the <hi>Angel,</hi> near <hi>Summerset</hi>-House in the <hi>Strand.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Dod</hi> Millenar in <hi>Princesstreet,</hi> next <hi>Drury-lane.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Last</hi> Stationer, at the <hi>Golden-Ball,</hi> near <hi>Doctors Commons.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Thompson,</hi> at the <hi>Half-Moon</hi> and <hi>Seven-Stars,</hi> in <hi>Eagle-Court,</hi> against <hi>Summerset-House.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Mr. <hi>Joseph Timm,</hi> at the <hi>Serpent</hi> in <hi>Southwark,</hi> over against the <hi>Spur</hi>-Inn, a Haberdasher of small-Wares.</item>
            </list>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:195937:2"/>
               <head>The Names of some of the Parents of the Children that have made use of this Virtuous Necklace, to their great Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sort, and Satisfaction, who are ready to testifie the same.</head>
               <list>
                  <item>A Child of the Countess of <hi>Northumberlands.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of the Lady <hi>Bartees</hi> at St. <hi>James</hi>'s.</item>
                  <item>A Child of my Lord <hi>Burley</hi>'s</item>
                  <item>The Children of Sir <hi>William Drake,</hi> in <hi>Buckinghamshire.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Sir <hi>Edward Turners</hi> in <hi>Essex.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Alderman <hi>Thomas</hi>'s in <hi>Pater-noster-Row.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Esq; <hi>Mountagues,</hi> at <hi>Epsom</hi> in <hi>Surrey.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Jenkins,</hi> Brewer near the Horse-Ferry, at <hi>West<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minster.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Jarvis,</hi> at the <hi>George</hi> in <hi>Milk-street.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>A</hi> Child of Mr. <hi>Shepherds</hi> Goldsmith, at the <hi>Grape</hi> in <hi>Lumbard-street.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Leaders,</hi> at the <hi>Turks-Head</hi> in <hi>Market-Street</hi> in St. <hi>James</hi>'s.</item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Alcocks,</hi> at the Cock in <hi>Cheap-side,</hi> near <hi>Milk street.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Greys,</hi> Suffer to the Kings Regiment in <hi>Scotland Yard.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mrs. <hi>Suttons</hi> a Sempstress, next the Rose-Tavern with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out <hi>Temple-bar.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Whites,</hi> Grocer in the <hi>Old-Baley.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Marstons,</hi> at the Queens-Head in <hi>Bell-yard,</hi> near <hi>Temple-bar.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Whiskers,</hi> Upholsterer in <hi>King-street Westminster,</hi> near the <hi>Abbey.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Grooms,</hi> in <hi>Windmill street,</hi> near <hi>Pickadilly.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Cadmors,</hi> Joyner in <hi>Noble-street.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of the mans at the sign of the City <hi>Hamburgh,</hi> near the <hi>Hermitage-Bridge</hi> in <hi>Wappen.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>John Bishops,</hi> in King <hi>Henry</hi>'s House in King <hi>Henry</hi>'s Yard in <hi>Nightingale-Lane.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Bricknels,</hi> a Brewer in <hi>Harts-born-Lane.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Whites</hi> Grocer, at the Three Sugar-Loaves in the <hi>Strand,</hi> against the <hi>Savoy.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>A Child of Mr. <hi>Flowers,</hi> Clerk of <hi>Katherine Coleman,</hi> in <hi>Pye-Alley</hi> in <hi>Fan-Church-Street.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>